Guide to the Charles Henry Gilbert Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Charles Henry Gilbert papers
1880-1927
SC0085
Gilbert, Charles Henry, 1859-1928.
1 Linear feet
Notes, field notebooks, and journal clippings containing observations on various species, particularly salmon.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
Administrative transfer, 1969.
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Associated Materials
Correspondence by Charles H. Gilbert can be found in the Ray Lyman Wilbur presidential papers, SC 064A, in the “Zoology” folders.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
Professor of zoology at Stanford University (1891-1925; emeritus 1926-1928).
Description of the Collection
Notes, field notebooks, and journal clippings containing observations on various species, particularly salmon.
Access Terms
Gilbert, Charles Henry, 1859-1928.; Stanford University. Department of Biological Sciences. Faculty.; Stanford University. Department of Zoology. Faculty.; Clippings.; Ichthyologists.; Notes.; Zoologists.; Zoology.
Collection Contents
- Papers, 1880-1927
  - Notebooks of Observations of Fish, 1893-1897 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Notebook of Journal Clippings, 1900-1912 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Journal Clippings, 1912-1925 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Salmon Notes, 1903 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Salmon Notes, 1909 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Salmon Notes, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Salmon Notes, 1912 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Miscellaneous, 1898-1913 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Untitled Field Notebook, 1880 (Box 2)
  - Unpublished Columbia River Notes, Summer, 1894 (Box 2)
  - Alaska, 1903 (Box 2)
  - Movements of Sockeye Salmon, 1909 (Box 2)
  - Sacramento River Trip, 1911 (Box 2)
  - Salmon, 1913 (Box 2)
  - Alaska Salmon Investigations, Itinerary and Notes, 1917 (Box 2)
  - Accounts, Itinerary, 1918 (Box 2)
  - Sacramento River, 1918 (Box 2)
  - Diary, 1921 (Box 2)
  - Alitak Packing Co., Chignik Lake, 1921 (Box 2)
  - Karluk Lake, 1921 (Box 2)
  - Alaska Peninsula, 1922 (Box 2)
  - Karluk Lake, 1922 (Box 2)
  - Karluk Lake, Hump Records, 1922 (Box 2)
  - Tagging, 1922 (Box 2)
  - Untitled Field Notebook, 1923 (Box 2)
  - Log of Summer, 1923 (Box 2)
  - Alaska, 1924 (Box 2)
  - Untitled Field Notebook, 1925 May 10-August 12 (Box 2)
  - Untitled Field Notebook, 1925 August 13-December 9 (Box 2)
  - Untitled Field Notebook, 1927 (Box 2)
  - Field Notes, 1927 (Box 2)